<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>distributed_system on Jefo</title>
    <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/tags/distributed_system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in distributed_system on Jefo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:21:52 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qizhengzou.github.io/tags/distributed_system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_14</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2022/ds_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:21:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2022/ds_summary/</guid>
      <description>topics Understanding lecture notes and tutorial questions. 1.Introduction A distributed system is defined as one in which components at networked computers communicate and coordinate their actions only by passing messages. The motivation of constructing a distributed system is resource sharing and collaborative computing Distributed system features. Concurrency No global clock Independent failure Distributed system challenges. Heterogeneity Openness Security Scalability Failure handling Concurrency Transparency Quality of Service 2.System Model Difficulties for</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_13</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2022/web-searching-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:21:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2022/web-searching-technologies/</guid>
      <description>Web Searching Technologies Some helpful web sites：
 A history of search engines:  http://www.wiley.com/legacy/compbooks/sonnenreich/webdev/history.html   Open source search engines written in Java:  http://java-source.net/open-source/search-engines   Robots:  http://www.robotstxt.org/wc/robots.html    Search Engines Architecture：
   Spiders (Web Crawler)：
 Automatically Retrieve web pages  Start with an URL, retrieving the web page Find all URLs on the web page and recursively retrieve not-yet searched URLs   Algorithmic Issues  Efficiency and Quality: how to quickly gather as many useful web pages as possible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_12</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2022/transaction-processing-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:21:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2022/transaction-processing-systems/</guid>
      <description>Transaction Processing Systems事务处理系统 File operations and Transaction operations： Definitions of Atomic Transactions ： Atomic Transaction: a sequence of data access operations that are atomic in the sense of: All-or-Nothing Serializability The ACID properties of a transaction in RM-ODP: Atomicity Consistency Isolation Durability What makes Database inc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_11</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2022/unix-fs-and-distributed-fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:21:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2022/unix-fs-and-distributed-fs/</guid>
      <description>Unix File Systems文件系统 File Systems： File system provides the most fundamental service for building any information systems. file storage, management and retrieve service. We look at two file operations: fp = open (“cs4274/exam”, r, 0); r = read (fp,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_10</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/consistency-and-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:36:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/consistency-and-replication/</guid>
      <description>Consistency and Replication一致性和复制 Replication of data: Why? To enhance reliability To improve performance in a large scale system Replicas must be consistent Modifications have to be carried out on all copies Problems with network performance It is needed to handling concurrency… 1.2.3-&amp;gt;Different consistency</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_09</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/group-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:36:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/group-communication/</guid>
      <description>Group Communication群组通信 Modes of communication： One-to-One Unicast 1&amp;lt;&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;1 Point-to-point Anycast 1-&amp;gt;nearest 1 of several identical nodes Introduced with IPv6; used with BGP routing protocol One-to-many Multicast 1-&amp;gt;many Group communication Broadcast 1-&amp;gt;all Groups: Groups allow us to deal with a collection of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_08</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/name-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:36:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/name-services/</guid>
      <description>Name Services 命名服务 Name, address, route： The name indicates what we seek Human readable Universal Resource Names (URNs) An address indicates where it is IP address, port A route tells how to get there Internet routing Name and IP-address Not 1 to 1 Mapping： One host may map to more than one name One server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_07</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/internetworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:36:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/internetworking/</guid>
      <description>Internetworking网际路由 Internet Structure: Network of Networks： Internet is in a hierarchical structure National/ International Backbone Providers (NBP) e.g. BBN/GTE, Sprint, AT&amp;amp;T, IBM, UUNet interconnect (peer) with each other privately, or at public Network Access Point (NAPs) Regional ISPs connect into NBPs Local ISP connect</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_06</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/socket-rpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:35:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/socket-rpc/</guid>
      <description>Socket Communication套接字通信（直接通信) Clients and Servers： A distributed system can be generally modeled by clients and servers (processes). Clients and servers are usually on different machines and they interact with each other via message passing. To offer a service, a server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_05</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/mutual-exclusion-election-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:35:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/mutual-exclusion-election-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Mutual Exclusion &amp;amp; Election Algorithms(互斥算法 &amp;amp; 选举算法) Mutual Exclusion Process Synchronization: Techniques to coordinate execution among processes One process may have to wait for another Shared resource (e.g. critical section) may require exclusive access Requirements of Mutual Exclusion Algorithms: A mutual exclusion algorithm should satisfy the following properties: Safety Property: The safety</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_04</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/logical-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:35:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/logical-time/</guid>
      <description>Logical Time Motivation of logical clocks: Cannot synchronize physical clocks perfectly in distributed systems. [Lamport 1978] Main function of computer clocks – order events If two processes don’t interact, there is no need to sync clocks. This observation leads to “causality” Causality（因果性）:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_03</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/physical-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:35:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/physical-time/</guid>
      <description>Physical Time Why Timestamps in Systems? Precise performance measurements Guarantee “up-to-date” or recentness of data Temporal ordering of events produced by concurrent processes Synchronization between senders and receivers of messages Coordination of joint activities Serialization of concurrent accesses to shared objects …… Physical time: Solar time 1 sec = 1 day / 86400 Problem: days are of different</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_02</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/distributedsystem-hongweidu-system-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:35:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/distributedsystem-hongweidu-system-modules/</guid>
      <description>System Modules Descriptive models for distributed system design: Physical model Most explicit description of a system. Capture hardware composition in terms of computers and their interconnecting networks. Architectural model Describes a systems in terms of computational and communication task performed by computational elements. Fundamental model Abstract perspective in order to study the individual aspects of a system. Three models are introduced: interaction model, failure model, and the security model. Difficulties</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_HongweiDu_01</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/distributedsystem-hongweidu-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:35:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/distributedsystem-hongweidu-intro/</guid>
      <description>Intr HongweiDu(堵宏伟) Topics Introduction Distributed Systems models Distributed Time and Clock Synchronization Socket Communication Remote Method Invocation(RMI) Group Communication Mutual exclusion &amp;amp; election algorithms Replication …… Motivation Resource sharing Computers connected by the network and share resources. Hardware sharing, software sharing, data sharing, service sharing.media stream sharing. Collaborative computing Parallel computing, distributed computing Definition A distributed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_base_02</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/system-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 08:45:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/system-models/</guid>
      <description>系统模型 简介 物理模型是描述系统的-个最显式的方法，它从计算机(和其他设备，例如移动电话)及其互联的网络方面考虑系统的硬件组成。 体系结构模型从</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DistributedSystem_base_01</title>
      <link>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/characteristics-of-distributed-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 10:24:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qizhengzou.github.io/2021/characteristics-of-distributed-system/</guid>
      <description>分布式系统的特征 简介 我们把分布式系统定义成一个其硬件或软件组件分布在联网的计算机上，组件之间通过传递消息进行通信和动作协调的系统。 我们定义的</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
